So for this particular exercise,
I want you to try practicing configuring it from scratch.
Because I want you to get familiar with
the files that are critical to how View Router works.
So as a general guidance,
use the View Router docs for reference.
I do not expect you to memorize all this.
In fact, if you do a lot of
copy and paste from the sample code, that's totally fine.
The goal is for you to here to configure,
get a feel for how things are being
basically configured out of raw directory.
Then other than that,
you can move any page components that you think is
relevant inside of your SeleView app.
Then after that, we'll go ahead and
upgrade the App.View to use
RouterLink and RouterView so that
everything renders correctly.
All right. Welcome back.
How was that experience with a little bit
harrowing from just all the configuration?
Yeah, I completely understand.
So we're going to do a run-through just again,
just to reiterate those steps and
well share some tips and tricks along the way.
So how this will work is we're going to go over to SeleView.
Let me go ahead and do SeleView.
Great. Then let's play around with this.
First thing first is we need to install View Router,
version, not version R, version 4.
There we go.
Then what we're going to do is we're going to go
ahead and configure our app.
Actually, let me go ahead and run it as well
so we can see the changes happening.
There we go. We're in it.
Okay. So inside of our main.js app,
we'll see that we don't have a router right now.
So let's go ahead and fix that.
Import Create Router from,
I usually prefer when I have the autocomplete,
but I'm fairly confident in this one.
Great. Yep. It's right.
So what we can do now is your const app,
is your create app.
Then to make it more declarative,
we'll do app.useRouter,
which I need to define in a second,
and then app.mount, whoops, not a board controller.
Then we can just define our router this way to create router.
We need to pass some options to it.
So the history on this is going to be Create WebHassHistory.
Again, the reason we're doing this is because it does
require some server configurations in order to get it to work on
the normal HTML5 mode.
So again, I'll leave it to you and the docs,
depending on how you're deploying it to do that.
But generally speaking, what you're doing is you want it to
redirect always to index.html,
and again, plenty of docs to support
probably wherever you're deploying it to.
In the meantime, WebHassHistory is what we're going to use,
because that is the most universal one in terms of
like ensuring that things don't break,
and that is a function that we need to run,
and then we need to be able to find the routes.
So just to do this slightly differently,
so you can actually see what's actually going on here,
we can actually just define the routes in here as well.
I separate them out into a file normally
to make it a little bit easier for management.
But again, to help seal the mental model a little bit more,
we're going to do it this way.
So inside of the components,
we can see what kind of pages do we already have.
Well, we already got three actually aptly named pages.
So let's go and create that folder for views,
and let's just move them over.
Yep. What does Vola want to do?
Oh, it knows I want to change it.
Great. Please do that for me.
I'm going to move that as well.
I'm going to trust it to do its thing. Great.
All right. So now we should have a bunch of things moved over.
But there was a good question that was asked earlier regarding,
it's nice for us to be explicit about where the file path is,
but anyone who's worked on a large app before will know that
when it comes to moving files,
that can be a bit of a pain when you're moving
up directories, down directories,
and isn't there an easier way to do this,
that it always refers to the root directory.
That way, no matter where you,
as long as you're not doing a ton of nested folders,
it should make life a lot easier.
And so the secret to this actually,
is that we actually do have that already built in,
and that's the at symbol.
And so when you do the at symbol, what that does is it says,
please go to the source folder,
and then start your file path from there.
And it's a really nice alias to have.
Now, I'm telling you this, and you might be like,
ooh, that sounds like black magic. It's not.
If you look inside of our V config,
in fact, this is the default to be honest,
but I'll just stick it to Cela V view.
You'll see here that there actually is an alias
being defined from V that says, hey, this is the at symbol,
and what I want you to do is automatically put
the file URL path to this dot slash source directory.
And so what this means is you can configure it
to whatever you want.
It doesn't have to be at,
but that does happen to be,
that happens to be a convention for a lot of applications.
So the at symbol is there for you,
if you want to simplify the fact
that you don't have to navigate now.
Wait, what folder am I in and what's going on?
Now that we have that, let's keep on going.
So first thing first, what kind of routes do we have?
Well, we're going to want to have a path for the homepage.
And so what component is that?
We're going to want to do the component for homepage.
All right, so here we have homepage,
but we need to import that.
So we have homepage from, let's use our handy alias,
components slash homepage dot view.
And that's super convenient because I don't have to think
where am I inside of the directory.
It's super, super nice.
Great, there was a comment in the audience that
we moved it to views, it's not in components anymore.
And that's correct, so that would break.
But from not having to think about what directory I'm in,
that is helpful.
There we go, look, everything's showing up.
Okay, then we have a path here.
And let's just go ahead and copy this block real quick
just to make this a little bit easier.
So we have login and then we have user.
Okay, user page, great.
And then we have user page, login page.
And this is how most of us would probably do this part.
Log in, oh, login is an L.
And then P or U for user page, there we go, save, great.
And then what we can do now is go inside of our app.view
for sale of view.
And rather than having this all be managed now
with the current page and whatnot,
we can actually make this a lot simpler.
So what we're going to do here is we're going to go ahead
and rather than put the component here,
we're just going to do, let me delete it first
to show you that everything was working.
Okay, great, it's gone.
Now we're just going to put router view.
And just like that, we have our pages.
Your routes are all defined to go to home page.
Yes, they are all defined to go to home page, good catch.
So we no longer need to track any of these things
because this is being now managed at the router level.
So in case you've seen duplicates,
you should not have duplicates.
There you go, don't need that component.
In fact, we don't need any of this
because all of this is doing is trying to do
all the programmatic things that viewrouter
will do for us out of the gate.
So I can actually just wipe out this whole thing.
And then we can no longer reference any of these things.
Let's comment that out real quick.
And then I think we're good as far as that goes.
Now we need to actually have the ability to switch it out.
So rather than use the A tags,
we're going to go ahead and use our anchors,
use our router link, sorry, one, two, router link.
Then we have this right here, one, two, router link.
Then we no longer have to worry about the click
and handling that and preventing that.
So all that can be deleted, clean that up.
And then instead of the href,
what we're going to do is we're going to move that
and then just do two.
And then to what?
And then we can go ahead correctly,
then go login, user, home.
Once we have that, there you go.
Everything works just as you would expect.
Okay.
So before I wrap up this exercise though,
the only thing I do want to show you,
if you go back to the boilerplate
that we created with view three,
and this time adding the fact that we have,
to do here's the router.
Okay.
You might notice something right here,
which is kind of interesting in that you can actually
write a function where the component is
in order to dynamically import that view.
And the reason this is a powerful technique,
while relatively simple, is that it will then
automatically generate a separate build chunk
that will lazy load when it's being loaded.
Because the problem right now,
if we look at how we're actually loading the route right now
in main.js, and say I love you,
we're importing every single component
that the app might possibly need to route to.
And if that app gets pretty large,
that's a lot to break apart.
So generally speaking, it's considered best practice
to go ahead and just like we see inside of this router.js,
oops not this one, we're looking at this one,
to go ahead and just import the path directly.
So I'm gonna go ahead and do that for us,
so that we can actually have that as a record of that.
So again, rather than have these two up here,
because we don't know when users are gonna log into that,
we know that home page needs to be imported.
So that cannot be dynamically imported.
But everything else, that has potential.
So we can go ahead and drop the imports here.
And the way it works is it's a function
that returns this path.
And that's what that looks like.
Delete that, delete that.
I think I had that right.
Let me just make sure one more time.
Oop, that one's not easy to read.
Import, yeah.
So, oh, I mistakenly did that the other way.
It is a function that does the import here,
and imports the specific path, just like that.
And so again, we can see user experience,
why as far as development goes,
you probably wouldn't really know the difference,
but this optimization can help a lot
when it comes to your apps going forward.